       Detecting tumors in brain scans
            This is semantic segmentation, where each pixel in the image is classified (as

            want to determine the exact location and shape of tumors), typically us , we
            as well.                                                                                  '1NNs 

      Automatically classifying news articles
           This is natural language processing (NLP), and more specifically text classifiRN
           tion, which can be tackled using recurrent neural networks                        Ns), ci\\TS vr
           Transformers (see Chapter 16).


     Automatically flagging offensive comments on discussion forums

           This is also text classification, using the same NLP tools.


     Summarizing long documents automatically
          This is a branch of NLP called text summarization, again using the same tools. 


     Creating a chatbot or a personal assistant
          This involves many NLP components, including natural language understanding 

          (NLU) and question-answering modules.


    Forecasting your company's revenue next year, based on many performance metrics 
         This is a regression task (i.e., predicting values) that may be tackled using any 
         regression model, such as a Linear Regression or Polynomial Regression model 
         (see Chapter 4), a regression SVM (see Chapter 5), a regression Random Forest 
         (see Chapter 7), or an artificial neural network (see Chapter 10). If you want to 
        take into account sequences of past performance metrics, you may want to use 
        RNNs, CNNs, or Transformers (see Chapters 15 and 16).


   Making your app react to voice commands
        This is speech recognition, which requires processing audio samples: since they 
        are long and complex sequences, they are typically processed using RNNs, CNNs, 
        or Transformers (see Chapters 15 and 16).


  Detecting credit card fraud
       This is anomaly detection (see Chapter 9).


  Segmenting clients based on their purchases so that you can design a different marketing 
  strategy for each segment

       This is clustering (see Chapter 9).


 Representing a complex, high-dimensional dataset in a clear and insightful diagram 
      This is data visualization, often involving dimensionality reduction techniques 
       (see Chapter 8).


 Recommending a product that a client may be interested in, based onpast purchases 

      This is a recommender system. One approach is to feed past purchases (and 
      other information about the client) to an artificial neural network(see Chap-



6 I Chapter 1: The Machine Learning Landscape

  ter 10), and get it to output the most likely next purchase. This neural net would
  typically be trained on past sequences ofpurchases across all clients.
Building an intelligent bot for a game
  This is often tackled using Reinforcement Learning (RL; see Chapter 18), which
  is a branch of Machine Learning that trains agents (such as bots) to pick the
  actions that will maximize their rewards over time (e.g., a bot may get a reward
  every time the player loses some life points), within a given environment (such as
  the game). The famous AlphaGo program that beat the world champion at the
  game of Go was built using RL.
This list could go on and on, but hopefully it gives you a sense of the incredible
breadth and complexity of the tasks that Machine Learning can tackle, and the types
of techniques that you would use for each task.

